S. KRISHNAN

Objective: To give my best in the field of engineering where in creativity hard work are recognized appreciated encouraged awarded for mutual benefit and growth.

Educational Details:

B. Tech (Mechanical Engg)

DME (Diploma in Mechanical Engg)

Email:

s.krishnan.ppc@gmail.com

Contact No:

Mobile: 94860 80560

Contact Address:

Door No: 301-2A, First Floor,

Bathalapalli-village,

Adhiyaman Engg College-Post.

Hosur.635 109.

Personal Details:

Gender : Male

Marital Status: Married

Nationality : Indian

Date of Birth : 9thApril 1977

Languages Known:

English, Tamil, Kannada & Hindi

Experience Summary

5+ Years of working experience in Press Shop - Cold Forging components manufacturing company as **Manager-Production**.

(ACE FORGE Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore)

4 Years of worked experience in Aerospace & Defense composite components manufacturing company as Engineer-Production .

(TATA advanced materials ltd., Bangalore)

4 years of worked experience in Machine fabrication company as Executive-Production (CS Aerotherm Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore)

5 years of worked experience in automobile industry: Cold Extrusions, Machining & Heat treatment as Production - shift in charge.

(Genau Extrusions Ltd, Hosur)

2 years of worked experience in Gears and Reduction gear boxes manufacturing company as Supervisor - Production .

(Shanthi Gears Limited, Coimbatore)

Expertise

Press Shop: Cold Extrusions, Hot Forging, Heat treatment, Machining, Deep drawing with transferring press and Progressive presses.

Machine shop: In Automobile Industries Having working knowledge in Boring, VTL, VMC, CNC hobbing and Grinding, all types of gear manufacturing, thread & Worm milling and assembling.

Fabrication: Tube and Sheet metal cutting, bending, welding, machine fabrication, assembling & Testing

Assembly: Reduction gear boxes, Air classifiers, Aerospace & Defense Composite manufacturing and assembling.

Production Planning and Execution: Man Power Management, Lean Six sigma, 6S,

Quality: Handling of all types of QA Instruments & Gauges, Vendor development and material follow up.

Quality Safety & Industrial Training

ISO IATF 16949:2016 awareness programme.

ISO 9001:2015 awareness programme AS 9100 rev C awareness programme NADCAP awareness programme

SAP PP troubleshoot, configuration, implementation

Academic Details

Qualification : B. Tech (Mechanical Engineer)
Institution : Rajasthan University

Percentage : 65.5 % Year of Passing : 2012

Qualification : Diploma in Mechanical Engineering.
Institution : Govt polytechnic, Krishnagiri.
Percentage : 81 % (first class with Distinction)

Year of Passing : April 1995.

WORK EXPERIENCE

M/s. ACE FORGE Pvt Ltd. Bangalore Aug 2014 to till date

The company is actively engaged in design, development & manufacturing of Precision **cold forgings** from Steel & Aluminum alloy and finishing with CNC machined components for Automotive, Locomotive, and Aerospace.

Customers:: RANE, KUN AEROSPACE, DEUTSCH, VST TILLERS

Designation: Manager - Production / Planning

KEY ACHIEVEMENT:

Improved OEE from 56% to > 80% in 2019

Improved ON TIME DELIVERY from 83% to > 96% in 2019

Implemented FIFO & KANBAN system and reduced idle time (No material) 0.05%.

Reduced TOOL BREAKAGES by implementing tool checking frequency monitoring.

Increased tool life from average 5000 Nos to 45000 Nos.

Trained & Coached team leaders and Operators on various topics & Skill based trainings

Fire fighting, 5S & Safety, Handling Instruments, Customer Specific Requirements(CSR), Awarenes on QMS.

Promoting Suggestions, KAIZENs, Continual Improvements.

Reduced rejection level 3500ppm to 2500ppm.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

Responsible for achieving KPI targets such as OEE.

Preparing Machine Capacity Plan, Monthly Production Plan, Weekly Production plan and follow up.

Responsible for reduction of downtime related to manpower, tool and machine

Implementation of route card system & traceability

Implementation of 4M Change Management.

Coordinating for timely availability of Raw Material

Responsible for coordinating of subcontracting activities

Responsible for training of subordinates.

Implementation of Lean management & reduction of waste.

Implementation of ERP system production & Planning.

Responsible for Risk analysis related to production & subcontracting activities.

Implementation of IATF 16949 & ISO9000 system related to production & Planning activities.

To ensure availability of Consumables and controlling the same.

To ensure updating machine Check list and Preventive Maintenance as per PMD Plan

Reviewing of Control Plans, Drawings, Tool Layouts and Providing Work Instructions and SOPs.

M/s.TATA ADVANCED MATERIALS LIMITED, Bangalore January 2010 to Jul 2014

The company is actively engaged in manufacturing of **composite** parts for Aerospace, Industrial & Defense customers: : **HAL, NAL, VSSC , FACC, GOODRICH, BOEING, P&W, IAE and GE aerospace** .

Designation: Engineer-Production / Planning

RESPONSIBILITIES:

To ensure Work Place Safety and Providing PPE and control on it.

Ensure Route Card System in place for traceability

Planning for Calibration of Instruments.

Manpower analysis by reviewing past week production and Manpower planning for next week.

Planning for Trainings to subordinates and providing the same.

Increasing Productivity by Effectiveness of A) Production as per Cycle time. B) Defect free Production.

C) Reducing Rejection rate. D) Corrective Actions for Losses on OEE

Improvement on Housekeeping by practicing '6S' activities.

Analyzing Tool breakages and average Tool life.

To study on 'Non conforming' products and control the same.

Implementation of QMS Procedures and Systems and monitoring the same.

Preparing Reports for MOP A) Monthly Production B) Monthly Rejection C) Monthly Scrap.

Capturing of **OEE** data and achieving the Target.

 $\label{lem:continually improve the production output by \ \textbf{lean manufacturing} \ techniques \ \& \ reduction \ in \ was tages.$

Providing On Job Training, Safety awareness.

Training end users on production planning transactions in SAP.

M/s. CS AEROTHRM PRIVATE LIMITED. Bangalore, June 2006 to January 2010

Manufacturer of Baking Machinery & Equipments and Air classifiers, Dryers, Curing Ovens Air classifiers, Cyclone Separators, Screw Conveyors for the following customers: Britannia, Grindwell Norton.

Designation: Executive-Production / Planning

Heading the shop floor for its Fabrication, Assembly & Testing activities with related to production planning.

Supervising, handling and arranging of workmen to carry out the production of company's products & achieving the maximum output within specified time frame

Pre planning the raw materials with related to Fabrication, assembly, testing and painting process

Overall scrap reduction, Overall cost reduction

System improvements

Member Kaizen, Tool managements sub committees.

M/s. GENAU EXTRUSIONS LIMITED, Hosur. January 2001 to May 2006

Manufacturer of **Cold Extrusion** products including machining and Heat Treatment for automobile industries like **Tata international Limited**, Chennai. **Spicer India Limited**, Dharwad.

Designation: Shift In charge - Production

Heading the shift activities in press shop comprising of 53 employees, hydraulic presses (200T to 800T),

Mechanical presses (100T to 1600T)

Responsible for Press Shop Efficiency.

Production Planning and control

System improvements.

Working in ERP.

Corrective and preventive action on NON CONFORMANCE.

Contribution for

Member - Cross Functional Team

Member - Kaizen, Management sub committees

M/s. SHANTHI GEARS LIMITED. Coimbatore. July 1995 to November 2000

Manufacturer of all types of gears and reduction gear boxes.

Supervising, and arranging of workmen to carry out the production of company's

Products & achieving the maximum output within specified time frame

Scheduling of Shop for Daily activities to get maximum output on machineries Boring,

Grinding, CNC hobbing, Thread & Worm milling, assembling

Manpower management by providing a systematic training with the help of work sequence sheets and achieving the target from them.

Maintaining process documents and Production reports for QMS standard.

Responsible for Gear shop Efficiency.

Declaration

I, **Krishnan**, affirm that the information compiled above is precise and accurate in its entirety to my knowledge.

Mobile: 94860 80560 (S.Krishnan)